<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Martín Rodriguez</title>
        <link>/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Martín Rodriguez</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 18:44:11 -0700</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Developing Music Apps for Samsung Active 2 Watch</title>
            <link>/posts/2020/04/developing-music-apps-for-samsung-active-2-watch/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 18:44:11 -0700</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/2020/04/developing-music-apps-for-samsung-active-2-watch/</guid>
            <description>My housemate was gifted a Samsung Active 2 Watch for her birthday. She wasn&amp;rsquo;t too thrilled about it, and I knew it had an accelerometer, so I asked if I could play around with it. I started thinking about using it for MIDI aftertouch effects using the accelerometer. I searched the Samsung app store to see if there were any existing apps with similar features. I discovered that the number of apps currently available was quite small, and unsurprisingly, there were no music-related apps whatsoever.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My housemate was gifted a Samsung Active 2 Watch for her birthday.
She wasn&rsquo;t too thrilled about it, and I knew it had an accelerometer, so I asked if I could play around with it.
I started thinking about using it for MIDI aftertouch effects using the accelerometer.
I searched the Samsung app store to see if there were any existing apps with similar features.
I discovered that the number of apps currently available was quite small, and unsurprisingly,
there were no music-related apps whatsoever. Most items in the store were either watch face skins or
fitness trackers.</p>
<p>My first step was to download Tizen Studio from Samsung and install it on my iMac. The installation was fairly painless.
Ideally, my goal was to create a native app for the watch, written in C++, to connect directly to the computer to transfer MIDI
information via bluetooth, without the need to connect to a separate phone app. After some troubleshooting (sometimes the watch
would skip asking for permissions, making it impossible to connect), I was able to connect and load the first template app, &ldquo;Hello Tizen&rdquo;
onto the watch. The next step is to figure out how to make different UI elements to display relevent info and for debug purposes.</p>
<p>Once I become more familiar with this development environment I may write a tutorial as a future post so that others don&rsquo;t have to struggle to find answers like I did.</p>
<p>To be continued&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
